# Diego Placido Acosta Torrez

System Engineer - Developer - Quality Assurance

(+591) 77932322 Cochabamba, Bolivia diegoacosta9239@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dieg o-acosta-torrez-71b148230/ https://actodi9239.github.io/portf olio-react/build/

PROFILE I am a technology enthusiast with experience in Front-end (React JS, Angular, Next JS) and Back-end (Express, .NET). I have skills in software quality doing automated testing, using tools such as Python, pyTest in API and Selenium, Mocha and Chai, integrated in BrowserStack and GitHub Actions for UI testing with Allure. I have 4 years of experience in IT, managing servers, equipment and routers, as well as having been an assistant in development laboratories at the Universidad Mayor de San Simón. I like to be able to meet my goals, work in a team and I have experience working under pressure.

## WORK **EXPERIENCE**

# **Universidad Mayor de San Simon**

**Laboratory Assistant | 2023-2024** 

Support to the maintenance department, server support and network maintenance, programming instructor and software developer using Java, Visual Basic, Python, Linux Ubuntu Server, router cisco and router mikrotik

#### **ISAPCAT**

# Technical department | 2020-2023

Develop well-structured, computer repair and maintenance and graphic design using photoshop, illustrator, wordpress, amazon web services, aiven, hostinger, azure devops github pages, render, netlify and react js.

#### Thermocontrol

# Web Developer Free Lancer | 2023

Develop well-structured, maintainable code and thoroughly test your, assist the Head of IT in assessing security of web applications and action required changes arising from 3rd party pen testing of systems using wordpress and hostinger.

## **Hybrid Scripts**

Web Developer | 2023

Internship where I learned new technologies, developing custom web software using Remix JS and React.

#### Thermocontrol

**Web Implementer** | **2020-2021** 

Parameterization of a CRM for the implementation, server configuration for deployment and training for the use of CRM software using EspoCRM and Ubuntu server.

# **Datos & Servicios**

**Technical Support | 2017-2020** 

Computer maintenance and repair, server configuration and maintenance, structured cabling, router configuration.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Diploma in commercial software quality management

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia

## **Systems engineer**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | 2016 - 2023, Cochabamba, Bolivia

#### **Bachelor of Humanities**

Corporación Educativa Kanata | 2003 - 2015, Cochabamba, Bolivia

#### SKILLS

Office | JavaScript | Java | TypeScript | Python | React JS | Angular | Azure DevOps | Selenium | Pipeline GitHub Actions | BrowserStack | PyTest | Wordpress | Illustrator | Photoshop | Figma | Git | GitHub | C# | Next JS | Remix JS | express | SpringBoot | Cisco | Mikrotik | Ubiquiti | Computer maintenance and assembly | Server maintenance | .Net

# IDIOMAS Spanish: Native

English: Medium

#### COURSES

## **Java Basic Module**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | September 2016, Cochabamba, Bolivia

# **Network Information Routing**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | May-June 2022, Cochabamba, Bolivia

#### **Spring Boot**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | April 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia

## **Installation and Configuration of Computer Networks**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | April 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia

# **Computer Maintenance**

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | April 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia

#### Backend Development with C# and .NET

Universidad Mayor de San Simón | Augst 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia

# **Bootcamp Fullstack React+Node.Js**

Enyoi Colombia | November 2024, Cochabamba, Bolivia